From Daily Wire published March
20th 2026 Your tax dollars could
still be on the line in fight
over trans surgeries for kids
Your tax dollars could still be
on the line in fight over trans
surgeries for kids The Biden
appointed judge sided with over
one dozen Democrat attorneys
general Mar 20th 2026 dailywire
com Listen to this article A
Biden appointed judge in Oregon
on Thursday said he would block
a Trump administration
declaration stating that
transgender medical procedures
for children are not safe or
effective U S District Judge
Mustafa Kasupay sided with more
than a dozen Democratic
attorneys general who challenged
the policy issued by Health and
Human Services Secretary Robert
F Kennedy Jr in December 2025 In
that declaration the Department
of Health and Human Services
said that sex rejecting
procedures for children and
adolescents are neither safe nor
effective as a treatment
modality for gender dysphoria
gender incongruence or other
related disorders in minors and
therefore fail to meet
professional recognized
standards of health care The
administration argued the
declaration was a general
statement of policy However
Kasupay indicated that Kennedy
did not follow the required
procedures in issuing it The
notion that I will go forward
and issue a declaration and see
if we can get away with it is
not a principle of governance
that adheres to the overarching
commitment to a democratic
republic that requires the rule
of law to be regarded and
respected and honored as a
sacred Kasupay said The judge
delivered a verbal ruling from
the bench and said a written
decision would follow The
declaration addressed treatments
including puberty blockers cross
sex hormones and surgeries like
mastectomies and vaginoplasties
New York Attorney General
Letitia James one of the
plaintiffs in the case
celebrated the ruling Health
care services for transgender
young people remain legal and
the federal government cannot
intimidate or punish the
providers who offer them James
said It is my duty and my
privilege to stand with trans
New Yorkers and their families I
will always fight for the LGBTQ
plus community The ruling comes
as the Trump administration has
taken steps to cut off federal
funding for all providers that
offer such treatments to minors
In December HHS posted rules to
bar hospitals providing
transgender procedures to minors
from participating in Medicare
and Medicaid programs and would
prohibit Medicaid's Children's
Health Insurance Program from
being used for transgender
procedures for individuals under